<Document>
# Phaethon Dynasty Lore Summary

<<<<<<< HEAD
[bold][color=#D2B48C]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] is an imperial state forged from the crucibles of war, ruin and espionage.

Long since the shattering of the Syndicate in the [color=yellow][bold]First and Last Corporate War[/color][/bold], and longer since the galaxy-spanning dominions of the ancient past, [bold][color=#D2B48C]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] has battle in its blood;
Formed by the last surviving battlegroup of the Syndicate Allies - the Phaethon armada - after a shaky retreat from Confederate forces, the few survivors of the Capitalist folly were forced into desolate sectors on the edge. Had not the Confederate forces experienced a schism in socio-economic beliefs,
the remnants of the once-glorious fleet would have surely been destroyed. Even with their pursuers recalled to bear their arms against themselves, the beginning of the Dynasty had shaky foundation, needing to scrap their vessels even more to mete out survival.
The difficulties they faced, while scarring of their populace - with plagues, shortages, genetic and technological limitations all rearing their sickles and bearing their toll - ultimately led to a robust society familiar with hardship.
Taking up residence in planetary systems surrounding the now-infamous Colossus sector, the growing populace of starved but hardy militants began to rebuild and regrow, ultimately forming an imperial dynasty off of their now-ancient military ranking - [bold][color=#D2B48C]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color].

Due to their proximity, [bold][color=#D2B48C]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] was the first political power to find the intense anomalies of the Colossus sector, the first to begin research on its phenomenon, and the first to coin its common term - The Monolith.
Such grand phenomenon was not ignored by the other galactic inhabitants, however...
While the [bold][color=#D2B48C]Dynasty[/bold][/color] has had times of instability and shaky future, it has persisted for over a century. Many of its citizens know little of its origins, but all share an unanimous hatred for the Trans-Solarian Federation instilled through generations of trauma.
It is thus little surprise that when the TSF reared their heads and their arms to claim the wonders and horrors of the Colossus sector, [bold][color=#D2B48C]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] armed their civilians and readied their weapons for the war to come.

Despite this unity through war and blood, the [bold][color=#D2B48C]Dynasty[/bold][/color] is not perfect; Since the recent rediscovery of the lives of those outside their homeland, many in the [bold][color=#D2B48C]Dynasty[/bold][/color] are torn between fundamental old world beliefs from their Syndicate ancestors, and the promises and truthes revealed by the
outside sectors. This looming threat of another bloody schism hangs over the throne, but in the time of war, strong leaders know the cost of letting down their guard.

Much of the [bold][color=#D2B48C]Dynasty[/bold][/color]'s military-industrial complex stems from refineries and industrial equipment from their first generation, but since reconnection with the rest of the galaxy, black-market trading has become their strongest economic niche - both in exports of illegal luxury goods from
outside the Colossus sector, to exports of preserved "syndicate" technology and data from the Monolith's anomalies.

Guerrilla strikes, AI corruption, propaganda floods, and sabotage operations leave the TSF
scrambling to take control of [bold]The Colossus Sector[/bold]. Their tactics are as much ideological as they are military, with their elite-operative Vanguard forces embracing the controversial techniques of the past and bringing even experienced TSF marines to their knees.
With neural leaks, anti-propaganda broadcasts, and liberated mythologies, [bold][color=#D2B48C]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] spreads rebellion in the Federation like a virus, harnessing their own knowledge of its societal shortcomings to cut it down. Their space stations, scattered across the galactic arm, have remained burdened with the weapons of
their ancestors.
=======
[bold][color=#636B2F]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] is a defiant imperial state born from the ruins of history’s most ruthless powers.
Once seperatist states that arose from the [color=yellow][bold]First and Last Corporate War[/color][/bold] fell to Trans-Solarian Federation occupation at the edge of inhabited systems. [bold][color=#636B2F]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] became a
crucible of survival, unity, and technological advancement. Here, a populace left scarred by foreign rule—composed of corporate war survivors and [bold]Syndicate[/bold] remnants—built a new empire from the ashes of old.
It became a dynasty of the discarded—fiercely independent and violently opposed to the oppressive regime
of the [bold][color=cyan]Trans-Solarian Federation (TSF)[/bold]


Emerging from the wreckage of the [color=yellow][bold]First and Last Corporate War[/color][/bold], [bold][color=#636B2F]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] holds deep ideological
scars. Its people are victims of war and betrayal.
Many, the children of [bold][color=#8B0000]Syndicate[/bold][/color] remnants who once served shadowy economic overlords, now pledge allegiance to [bold][color=#636B2F]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color]; the decendents of the last [bold][color=#8B0000]Syndicate[/bold][/color] commanders.
They are united by a shared hatred of foreign states and a vision of an isolationist empire.
The dynasty is not perfect; it is torn between old world [bold][color=#8B0000]Syndicate[/bold][/color] ideology and new idealists,
funded by black markets, and surviving on an industry of salvaged technology.  Though small, its industrial and technological, and military complex rivals that of much larger enemy forces. Its culture of asymmetrical warfare and geographical advantages make it nearly impossible to crush.


Guerrilla strikes, AI corruption, propaganda floods, and sabotage operations leave the TSF
scrambling to take control of [bold]The Colossus Sector[/bold]. Their tactics are as much ideological as they are military. With neural
leaks, anti-propaganda broadcasts, and liberated mythologies, [bold][color=#636B2F]The Phaethon Dynasty[/bold][/color] spreads rebellion in the Federation like a virus. Their space stations, scattered across the Colossus, remain off every map.
>>>>>>> parent of 397f9b3c01 (giga troll)


</Document>
