<Document>
# Roleplay Rule 8
## Safe Zones: Sanctuary and Conduct

[color=green][bold]Safe Zones[/bold][/color] (Colonial Outpost, Medical Dispatch, and a 256m radius around each) are a neutral sanctuary areas for all players, regardless of group or affiliation. Their purpose is to provide a secure environment for roleplay, diplomacy, medical treatment, and new player orientation.

All factions, military and non-military, agree on the following treatment of these two specific safe zones.

[color=blue][bold]Colonial Outpost[/bold][/color]

Colonial Outpost is classed as a Demilitarized Zone. It is the primary economic and civilian port for the sector whose destruction would be economically unwanted for all parties and acts as an outpost for TSF and non-TSF aligned civilian and economic interests, sponsored by the TSF.

In addition, it acts as a spot for diplomacy and negotiations between various factions.

These are the base restrictions set in place for Colonial Outpost and Medical Dispatch of which all factions agree to follow.

Colonial Outpost Restrictions:
- Openly carrying weaponry within Colonial Outpost outside of dedicated security personnel or the Colonial Liason to enforce the DMZ.
- Refusing to obey Station Traffic Controller or Colonial Liason regarding valid and reasonable docking orders.
- Causing trouble in Colonial Outpost or nearby ships, such as starting fights, attacking, or disrupting the peace.
- Unauthorized or prolonged docking of ships without permission from the Colonial Liason or Station Traffic Controller. Outpost staff are exempt.
- Attacking or attempting to destroy Colonial Outpost, ships within 256 meters, or otherwise engaging in ship combat that risks the safety of Colonial Outpost and shisp within this range.
- Otherwise using Colonial Outpost as a staging ground for illegal activities, or using it to escape active combat.

The Colonial Liason (CL) and, if missing, the Station Traffic Controller (STC) and Security Guard are the main authorities regarding the Demilitaried Zone of the Colonial Outpost. They are legally allowed to bar your ship from docking if it would bring conflict to Colonial Outpost.

[color=blue][bold]Medical Dispatch[/bold][/color]

Medical Dispatch is classed as a Hospital Zone. It is meant for sheltering the wounded and treating both Civilians and Military Personnel of any faction. As a location dedicated to medical care, its neutrality is respected by all parties.

Medical Dispatch Restrictions:

- Bringing weaponry into Medical Dispatch, unless you are a member of the Medical Dispatch, a security guard, or have permission from the Director of Care.
- Military faction ships are required to request authorization to dock before entering, forceful entry or forced docking by one is a violation of the Safe Zone.
- Causing trouble in Medical Dispatch or nearby ships, such as starting fights, attacking, or disrupting the peace.
- The prolonged docking of non-medical ships, especially military ships, who are not performing, assisting in, or requiring medical treatment without authorization from Medical Dispatch staff. Dispatch staff are exempt.
- Attacking or attempting to destroy Medical Dispatch, ships within 256 meters or otherwise engaging in ship combat that risks the safety of Medical Dispatch and shisp within this range.
- Otherwise using Medical Dispatch as a staging ground for illegal activities, or using it to escape active combat.

The Director of Care (DoC) and if missing, active emergancy responders onboard Medical Dispatch are the main authorities regarding the Hospital Zone of Medical Dispatch. They are legally allowed to bar your ship from docking if it would bring conflict to Medical Dispatch.

[color=red][bold]Violations of Safe Zones[/bold][/color]

Violating a Safe Zone results in responses according to the severity of the violation and depending on your affiliation.

- All Violators are barred from Safe Zones and lose all protections from Safe Zones until detained.
- Civilian Violators, as well as Military Violators who surrender peacefully, can be detained by any player with reasonable use of force and must be handed over to Colonial Outpost Security Guards or the Colonial Liason for processing, with punishments ranging from including fines, jail time, and sale of assets.
- Violators of a Military Faction who refuse to surrender may be declared violating the treaty and be considered a rogue element or a traitor for acting against the interests of their faction, and are allowed to be hunted by any player of any faction, including their own, to be brought to justice.

[color=yellow][bold]Admin Summary:[/bold][/color]
Violating a Safe Zone or causing trouble within one without valid IC reasoning will be handled with administrative action. 
Attempting to take over a Safe Zone or destroy it without administrative permission will result in administrative action.
Staff may intervene in cases of abuse or unclear situations.

</Document>